# Jeff Jenkins

Chicago, IL 60613 | 305-968-1809 | jjenkins120@gmail.com

Github: jjenkins120 | Medium: @jjenkins120 | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/jeff-jenkins-a08b3b51

### JOB TITLE

Entry-level full stack developer with experience in ruby-on-rails and javascript-related programming. Passionate about small-business, international, and psychosocial development, education, social justice, and the arts. Possess extensive experience in project planning, implementation and completion, in addition to strong skills in organizational and interpersonal development. Experience working in diverse industries to include government, international development, not-for-profit, for-profit small business, higher education and consultative sales. Enthusiastic to learn more skills in object-oriented programming.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Entry-level experience with Ruby, Rails, Javascript, React, React Native, Redux, HTML, CSS, Semantic UI, Bootstrap UI, and Git.

### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

Muse - Github: iienkins120/muse-frontend, iienkins120/muse-backend | Demo: https://voutu.be/stl8TwQoS98

Social Media App for Artists where Artists can be inspired by other work, regardless of medium, and contribute work based on those inspirations. Artists can track other artists' inspirations as well.

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Incorporated Ruby on Rails for backend API complete with complex modeling structure to include multiple self-referential and self-containing models.
- Employed React with Redux and Semantic UI for frontend development
- Included complete CRUD functionality associated with user profiles, posts, and comments.

Vegqie Delight - Github: ioannabpark/mod3-project | Demo: https://voutu.be/5cQxizZCYBs

Social Media Dating App designed specifically for vegetarians. Upon login, users are paired with other users and can choose to match with those users. Matches are stored in the user's profile.

- Utilized Ruby on Rails for backend API
- Incorporated Vanilla Javascript and Bootstrap UI for frontend development
- Included complete CRUD functionality associated with user's profile

#### **EXPERIENCE**

IES Abroad Customized Program Manager Chicago, IL

08/2018 - 04/2020

- Managed 60-70 customized study abroad programs, working collaboratively with 30+ IES Abroad Centers located worldwide.
- Served as the primary contact for colleges and universities in the Mid-Atlantic, OH, KY, NJ, NY, and WV on all matters related to faculty-led and customized programs.
- Drafted and revised program proposals and program pricing. Negotiated with partners to arrive at contractual agreements.

University of Miami, Study Abroad

Assistant Director

Coral Gables, FL 07/2015 - 08/2018

- Managed semester-long and short-term programs in Africa, Asia, and Pacific regions consisting of 100-150 outgoing and 50-100 incoming students annually.
- Primary contact with overseas counterparts regarding safety and security, curriculum management, housing, and exchange agreement management for programs within territory.

### **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School

Chicago, IL (Remote)

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

08/2020 - 11/2020

University of Miami Master of Science, Higher Education Student Life and Development Coral Gables, FL

Bachelor of Arts, International Studies and Religious Studies

12/2014

## **NOTABLE SERVICE**

Peace Corps Thailand

Uttaradit. Thailand 01/2008 - 01/2010

Community-Based Organizational Development Volunteer